Young people are the solutions for tomorrow.
Young people are the solutions for all the
worries.
Young people, if you stay with them,
you will be full of energetic.
But the advice I give to the young people
is also the advice I give to myself.
That nothing is easy.
Nothing is free.
If you want to be successful, you have to
pay the price.
Alibaba 18 years to today's size,
yeah we are lucky, but we work much harder!
Than most of the people!
We never sleep well and sound in the evening.
I traveled last year 867 hours a year, in
the plane.
I'm working hard, my team is working very
hard.
18 years we work like normal company 70 years.
Day and night.
Nothing is free.
Nothing is easy.
You have to think different, you have to do
different.
Early days in my company, when some ideas
come to my desk,
"Jack this a great idea!" and I look at everybody,
everybody say it is a good idea, I normally
threw it into the rubbish.
Because everybody says it is good.
Then all the other people thinking, if everybody
says this is gonna be very tough,
I'm very interested in that tough question
and I pick up and say,
"How can we do it in a different way?"
This is to be unique, to be different.
And the third, this is my advice and this
is also, I'm telling myself every day.
Today is very tough, tomorrow is tougher,
the day after tomorrow is beautiful,
but most people die tomorrow evening.
You have to work very hard, every tough day,
every tough situation,
problems you meet, that is the training of
yourself.
When you graduate in your school, you just
started your career of learning.
When you got a PhD diploma, a bachelor diploma,
this is just a certificate your parents paid
the tuition.
For 4 years.
Your real challenge is when you leave the
college, the real life starts,
the real exam starts, the real test starts.
That's life!
So, one thing you are lucky as I said, if
students cannot survive,
99.9% of people in the world cannot survive.
Only you have this confidence, you will be
able to face the challenge of future.
If you have 20-30 years, please find a good
boss, not necessarily a good company,
learn from the boss, learn how to do it.
When you're 30-40 years old, try to do something
yourself, if you really wanna try.
When you're 40-50 years old, do things that
you are good at,
after 20 years of learning you should do something
you're good at.
When you're 50-60 years old, spend your time
supporting young people.
When you are over 60 years old, spend time
with your grandchildren.
That is normally a lot of people like that.
So when you are a graduate or when you're
just in the university, don't think about,
"I want resign from the school and be another
Bill Gates, because Bill Gates left Harvard."
There's only one Bill Gates in the world.
When you graduate find a company,
most important find a good boss, that can
train you, discipline you.
Tell you what is good and right.
It's more important than a good company.
Of course, a good company, a good boss even
better.
And then, continue your life.
It's all about a partner.